ireland.com 2010-03-23

# privacy policy - Ireland.com

## Privacy Policy

### Introduction

Ireland.com has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices of Ireland.com.

You can access our site and utilise a number of our services without providing any information at all. However, anyone who registers for Ireland.com services provides basic contact and demographic information. We do develop general - not specific to any individual - reports for our advertisers. The people that make it possible for visitors to use Ireland.com for free - our advertisers - need this information to determine how effective their advertising investments are. Ireland.com will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any third party without your express permission except where applicable for the purpose of supplying the service for which you have registered.

We do not follow your browsing path outside of our websites.

**Irish data protection commissioner:**  
Further information on your data privacy rights are available on the website of the Irish data protection commissioner, [www.dataprivacy.ie](http://www.dataprivacy.ie/)

### Information Ireland.com collects:

**Optional sign ups:**  
If you wish to utilise certain services located on specific sections of Ireland.com, you must sign up. Services that currently require some form of sign up include:  
Participation in competitions / promotions / surveys;   
Rating reviews;  
Feedback and content;  
The information collected when you sign up for a service can include an email address and name. When signing up for a service, you may also "opt-in" to various email notifications or offers (see opt-in procedures below).

**Polling:**  
Ireland.com offers interactive polls so you can easily share your opinions with others and see what other Ireland.com users think about important issues. Name, email address and country information for each participant is retained temporarily.

**Cookies:**  
Certain sections of the site use cookies to maintain single user sessions as well as to aggregate broad demographic data as it relates to user behaviour. You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information back from the browser. You can find out more about the use of cookies on: [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)

**"Tell a Friend" feature:**  
You can electronically forward a link of an item to someone else by clicking the link at the bottom of an item. You provide a valid email address for both the sender and the recipient in order to ensure that the service functions properly and to inform the recipient who sent the story. There is also an option to include a name which is only used for the email salutation. None of this information is used for any other purpose.

**Information automatically recorded:**  
We record your IP address, browser's user agent, and referring address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our website and to identify unique users. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information.

**Auditing our traffic figures:**  
We also provide our log file data to ABC electronic auditing bureau on a regular basis to verify our traffic figures to the website. The information is used solely for auditing purposes.

Finally, the data may on occasion of abuse or harassment be used to find and locate individuals abusing the network system and or services of Ireland.com. In these cases this data may be passed on to appropriate individuals, organisations or companies, if specifically requested.

**Advertisers:**  
Ireland.com may perform statistical analyses of user behaviour in order to measure interest in the various areas of our site (for product development purposes) and to inform advertisers as to how many consumers have seen or "clicked" their advertising banners. We may also use demographic and preference information to allow advertising banners on our website to be targeted, in aggregate, to the readers for whom they are most pertinent. This means that readers may see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer's experience and the effectiveness of the ads. In this statistical analyses and banner advertisement targeting, we will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form. Personal information about you as an individual subscriber will not be provided to any third party without your consent.

We use a third-party advertising company to place ads when you visit our website. Our third-party advertising company also separately places or recognises a cookie file on your browser in the course of delivering advertisements to Ireland.com. They may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. For full details of our third-party advertising technology's company terms and conditions see: <http://www.adtech.info/cookie_opt-out/>

**Surveys & competitions:**  
From time to time our site requests information from users by means of surveys or competitions. Participation in these surveys or competitions is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and delivery address), and demographic information (such as address, age and income level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. No personal information will be retained for longer than is necessary or used for any undisclosed purpose.

Promotions and competitions that run on Ireland.com may be sponsored by companies other than Ireland.com or may be co-sponsored by Ireland.com and another company.

Ireland.com or its sponsors or business partners may with your expressed permission, from time to time, send you e-mails regarding its products and services.

**Email:**  
Using the email addresses provided on registration, Ireland.com may contact you regarding your premium email 

**External links:**  
This site contains links to other sites. Ireland.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

**Children’s Safety**  
The safety of children using the internet is very important to Ireland.com. It is primarily the responsibility of parents and guardians to monitor their children’s usage of the internet, though Ireland.com will take all reasonable steps not to compromise children’s rights and interests.

**Security:**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100 per cent secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Ireland.com cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**Opt-in:**  
Our site provides users with the opportunity to opt-in to receive promotional/marketing information from Ireland.com and select advertisers. To unsubscribe please email unsubscribe@digitalworx.ie and enter your e-mail address. 

**Correcting and updating:**  
Ireland.com offers users the ability to change certain personal identifiable information (e-mail address,) collected during the sign up process for specific services.

**Special interest sites:**  
Ireland.com provides certain services in conjunction with third parties. These third parties have their own security and privacy policies. You are advised to review these separately.

Ireland.com also offers you the opportunity to post, submit and exchange content and information on publicly accessible areas. A publicly accessible area is any area of Ireland.com that is accessible by the general public and may be accessed through an index link from a search engine. You may submit, post and exchange material and information in such areas, but should exercise caution in disclosing any personal information that may identify you, or others, personally. Remember that this information may remain indefinitely in the publicly accessible area of the Service. Also, depending on the particular Service, other users may also be able to view two or more of your individual postings collectively.

You are solely responsible for any personally identifiable information that you disclose and disseminate on publicly accessible areas. If you have a concern about any personally identifiable information you have posted on any publicly accessible areas and are unable to delete or edit it, please contact us at:

**What Else you Should Know about Privacy:**  
It is recommended that you close your browser when you have finished your user session. This will make it more difficult for others to access your personal information and correspondence specifically if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You agree that as an individual you, and in no way Ireland.com, are responsible for the security of, and access to, your own computer. You agree that you are aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet that this information can be collected and used by others. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your usernames and passwords and any account information. Our Websites may contain links to other websites, and you should be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices on other websites.

**Contacting the website:**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, or the security practices of this site, you can contact:
